<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xierumeng's Website</title>
    <description>For all things Xierumeng.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 14:40:25 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 14:40:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>1-2. Admission Information Form</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part of a 3-part series on the University of Waterloo’s application process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s topic will be on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca/future-students/admissions/admission-information-form&quot;&gt;admission information form&lt;/a&gt;.
This form is mandatory to be considered in the engineering admissions process, and there is a hard submission deadline.
Miss the deadline, and you will be rejected unless you appeal with a very good reason.
You are expected to create an account in &lt;a href=&quot;https://uwaterloo.ca/quest/&quot;&gt;Quest&lt;/a&gt;, where the form and other administrative information are located.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The form consists of several sections.
In some parts, you will answer short questions, limited to several hundred characters.
In other parts, you will fill out extracurricular activities, previous or current employment, courses, skills, and other requested information.
You will also indicate your second engineering choice in case you do not get into your first.
Please note that you are &lt;a href=&quot;https://profbillanderson.com/2013/01/02/computer-engineering-or-software-engineering/#comment-227&quot;&gt;not penalized&lt;/a&gt; when being considered for your second choice if you don’t get your first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a good AIF, good extracurricular activities and employment are important.
What the admissions team is looking for, I have no clue.
I speculate that activities requiring soft skills such as leadership, teamwork, and organization are particularly valuable, as well as activities requiring creativity and perseverance.
I also speculate that activities related to the program of choice will be helpful for the AIF.
It is also important to participate in the various contests hosted by UW, such as the Canadian Computing Competition (CCC) and Euclid Mathematics Contest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AIF is like a resume and cover letter; it is a mechanism which allows you to distinguish yourself from their peers and to show why UW would be a good fit for them.
The AIF also allows the applicant to explain circumstances that may have affected their academic performance.
The AIF is &lt;a href=&quot;https://profbillanderson.com/2014/01/04/scoring-your-aif/&quot;&gt;marked out of 5 points&lt;/a&gt;.
Generally, most AIFs will be marked as 3 for an average applicant with average extracurriculars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have filled out the AIF, it must be saved or submitted, otherwise, all work will be lost.
I suggest writing responses on another document before copy-pasting it into the form.
This information also useful for other purposes not related to the AIF, such as your resume and/or applications to other university programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important information to take away is to participate in extracurricular activities and contests hosted by the University of Waterloo in order to increase the AIF mark, therefore increasing the chance of being accepted into the program of choice.
However, high school marks and the AIF are not the only factor in determining chances of being accepted. I will discuss the next topic in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/1-1&quot;&gt;1-1. High School Marks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1.3 Video Interview (coming soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/1-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/1-2</guid>
        
        
        <category>blogUW</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>1-1. High School Marks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a 3-part series on the University of Waterloo’s application process. In this series, I cover high school course marks, the admission information form (AIF), and the video interview. In this series, I will refer to the applicant as “you”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s topic will be on high school marks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended high school in Ontario, so I will focus on the Undergrad (101) process.
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ouac.on.ca/&quot;&gt;Ontario Universities’ Application Centre&lt;/a&gt; (OUAC) is also where to submit the three (or more) applications to various university programs.
UW only accepts one application to an engineering program, but you will also get a chance to choose a second choice in the AIF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ontario high schools will send grade 11 and first semester grade 12 marks to the OUAC.
As second semester progresses, high schools will update the OUAC with second semester grade 12 midterm marks.
Universities will take the first batch and/or the second batch to use for their admissions process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grade 11 marks are generally only useful for early admission.
What’s more important is to maintain high marks in the first semester of grade 12 and in the first part of second semester, as those are what the universities will focus on.
Even though my marks in grade 11 were not very good, I focused on my studies in grade 12 and managed to get accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. William Bishop is the Director of Admissions for the Faculty of Engineering at the University of Waterloo, and maintains a blog on engineering admissions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://theroadtoengineering.com/&quot;&gt;The Road to Engineering&lt;/a&gt;.
In this blog, he writes about the admissions process, and gives useful insights on how the admissions team gives offers to applicants.
There are nice graphs displaying the chance of admission given an average mark.
Also check out Dr. William Anderson’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://profbillanderson.com/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; for information on previous years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grade inflation has become a problem in the past few years, and so there exists an &lt;a href=&quot;https://globalnews.ca/news/4405495/waterloo-engineering-grade-inflation-list/&quot;&gt;adjustment factor&lt;/a&gt;, depending on the high school.
On average, this adjustment factor is 16%. How this adjustment factor affects admissions, I have no clue.
However, I can speculate that having a lower adjustment factor is better.
I believe the Faculty of Mathematics does not include an adjustment factor in their admissions process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A conditional offer of acceptance will be sent out to the lucky ~10% in May (or earlier, depending on the round).
You will be expected to maintain their second semester grade 12 average above a certain threshold, typically 80 to 85%.
Once this condition is met, you will be fully accepted into the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important information to take away is to maintain high grade 12 marks in order to increase the chances of being accepted into the program of choice.
However, marks are not the only factor in determining chances of being accepted. I will discuss those next topics in the next 2 posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-0. The Right Fit (coming soon)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/1-2&quot;&gt;1-2. Admission Information Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/1-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/1-1</guid>
        
        
        <category>blogUW</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8. The 6 types of exam of questions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/comics/008-HNZc5ZN3RgGo7RiU-O2NFp7elfMM0rKzB.png&quot; alt=&quot;PAGE 008&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top right question taken from the ECE 105 F18 Final Examination. Hopefully I answered that correctly. For the bottom centre, I got the question from &lt;a href=&quot;http://phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=993&quot;&gt;PHD Comics&lt;/a&gt;. For the bottom right, I would like to thank &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/swegmesterflex&quot;&gt;u/swegmesterflex&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/uwaterloo/comments/9zkfo0/can_i_get_an_f_in_chat/&quot;&gt;meme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comics/008</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comics/008</guid>
        
        
        <category>comic</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7. Big brain angry Mr. Goose</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/comics/007-i2qgvztArKHR00BG-PpGsuSQ3dobNOKN0.png&quot; alt=&quot;PAGE 007&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comics/007</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comics/007</guid>
        
        
        <category>comic</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6. Pi Day Meme Contest Submission</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/comics/006-3XO8dBc2HkvcXgaI-xMeCe50A2cmbxjet.png&quot; alt=&quot;PAGE 006&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comics/006</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comics/006</guid>
        
        
        <category>comic</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5. The 5 Stages of 1st Years Getting a Quiz Back</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/comics/005-hTzrdVyVKq4lsfcm-EER97Av5mspXXQA5.png&quot; alt=&quot;PAGE 005&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comics/005</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comics/005</guid>
        
        
        <category>comic</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4. Unforgiving marking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/comics/004-LF0TdVU4VzZTdKes-TMoALYkBw7cug7RG.png&quot; alt=&quot;COMIC 004&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comics/004</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comics/004</guid>
        
        
        <category>comic</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3. Beyond Help</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/comics/003-jSxAjhULzRECx4ZE-7U47WlOzbCehZtXq.png&quot; alt=&quot;COMIC 003&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comics/003</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comics/003</guid>
        
        
        <category>comic</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2. All I want for Christmas...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/comics/002-jpY9uBsONIxPxBSX-HuhuRVaFoyO477to.png&quot; alt=&quot;COMIC 002&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comics/002</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comics/002</guid>
        
        
        <category>comic</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>1. ECE 2023's Policy 71</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/comics/001-Ck2ovpBfjcWouvAp-uY4uorkvR7FYehKY.png&quot; alt=&quot;COMIC 001&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comics/001</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comics/001</guid>
        
        
        <category>comic</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
